To become a psychologist, you first need to major in usually psychology in your under graduate career.
The under graduate is a four year course study that you'd do in a college or university.
After completing your Bachelor's degree in psychology.
Before you can become a practicing psychologist.
You need to go to graduate school.
To do this you first must take the graduate entrance exam or the GRE.
And apply to psychology programs.
Psychology is a, the doctorate program in psychology is a four year course of study.
And upon completion, you would obtain the degree of PhD.
There are different areas of psychology.
There's research psychology, there's chronicle psychology.
And depending on what it is, you wish to do.
Will determine your course of study.
But let's focus on chronicle psychologist.
As that's what, you're most familiar with.
A chronicle psychologist is a person who engages in therapy with patients.
To help them with emotional problems.
It should be noted that a psychologist is different than a psychiatrist.
Psychiatrist is a medical specialty and requires a medical degree.
Psychiatrist are allowed to prescribe medicines.
And typically do not focus on therapy.
Psychologists are not allowed to prescribe medicines.
And really focus primarily on therapy, with the patients.
Once you've completed your graduate training on psychology.
Typically, there are some period of internship.
In which you'll work with practicing psychologists.
Under their supervision, you learn your clinical skills.
And will be ready to take the state license exam.
Once you've taken the state license exam and passed successfully.
You'll be ready to practice independently, as a psychologist.